Heartbreak has inspired thousands of songs, books and films, and, however much we try to avoid it, is something we are all likely to experience at some point in our lives.
伤心激发了成千上万首歌曲、书籍和电影的创作，而且，无论我们多么努力去避免，它都是我们在人生某个时刻很可能会经历的事情。
But what exactly is heartbreak, and how does it affect us?
但心碎究竟是什么，它又如何影响我们呢？
Heartbreak often occurs after a breakup, bereavement or the loss of a family member or friend.
心碎通常发生在分手、丧亲或失去家人或朋友之后。
When this happens, we experience grief, which heartbreak is a form of.
当这种情况发生时，我们会经历悲伤，而心碎正是悲伤的一种形式。
And it doesn't just have emotional effects – it affects us physically too.
它不仅产生情感上的影响——它也会在生理上影响我们。
The word 'heartbreak' comes from the physical response to loss, described on BBC's The Why Factor as feeling like someone is 'physically squeezing the heart', though our hearts don't experience any real damage.
"心碎"这个词源于对失去的生理反应，在BBC的《为什么》节目中被描述为感觉像有人在"物理上挤压心脏"，尽管我们的心脏并未遭受任何真正的损害。
Psychologist Guy Winch told the BBC that, although we tend to feel pain viscerally, the pain of heartbreak actually comes from the brain, and is a by-product of love.
心理学家盖伊·温奇告诉BBC，尽管我们倾向于本能地感受到痛苦，但心碎的痛苦实际上来自大脑，是爱的副产品。
The emotional pain may be understandable, but why do we experience such physical pain?
情感上的痛苦或许可以理解，但我们为什么会经历如此强烈的生理痛苦呢？
According to Florence Williams, author of Heartbreak: A Personal and Scientific Journey, when you connect with someone on an intimate level, your bodies can actually sync up.
《心碎：一段个人与科学的旅程》一书的作者弗洛伦斯·威廉姆斯说，当你与某人建立亲密层面上的联系时，你们的身体实际上可以同步。
Cortisol levels and respiration rates can align, and heartbeats might regulate during sleep.
皮质醇水平和呼吸频率可以一致，心跳在睡眠中也可能调节。
When that partner is no longer there, our body reacts negatively to this change, causing us pain.
当那个伴侣不在时，我们的身体会对这种变化做出负面的反应，给我们带来痛苦。
The reason for this is evolutionary, Williams says.
威廉姆斯说，这种原因是进化上的。
The nervous system acts as though it is under threat because, as social animals, we feel far more comfortable and safe with others than when alone.
神经系统表现得好像受到了威胁，因为作为群居动物，我们与他人在一起时远比独处时感到更舒适和安全。
Therefore, the symptoms of heartbreak are a perfectly natural response, however hard they may be to cope with.
因此，心碎的症状是一种完全自然的反应，无论它们多么难以应对。
So, if you have a broken heart, what can you do?
那么，如果你心碎了，你能做些什么呢？
Healthline suggests you should take time to grieve, reconnect with yourself, and surround yourself with supportive friends.
Healthline网站建议，你应该花时间悲伤，重新与自己建立联系，并让自己被支持的朋友包围。